(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T22:57:48.720764",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
遥か昔、
A long time ago...
未知の海に沈んだとされる伝説の都市...
...in a legendary city said to have sunk in an unknown sea...
アトロボリス。
Atrobolis.
そんな誰もいないはずの海の底に
At the bottom of that sea, where no one should be,
ロボットの少女が一人。
is a lone robot girl.
彼女の歌声は 都市を再び浮上させる唯一の鍵。
Her singing voice is the sole key to making the city resurface.
「今宵...この街を再び地上へ...」
"Tonight... this city once again to the surface..."
これは 一夜限りの夢の祭典。
This is a festival of dreams, for one night only.
泡となって消える都市の、最後の物語
The last story of the city that disappears as foam...
Ah ah ah ah ah
だめだめだめ 脳みその中から
No, no, no, from inside my brain...
やめろバカとわめくモラリティ
...morality screams, "Stop it, you idiot!"
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン 半端なくラブと
Darling baby, darling, with an insane amount of love...
きらめき 浮き足立つフィロソフィー
...and a sparkling, restless philosophy.
死ぬほど可愛い うわめづかい
An upturned gaze so cute it could kill,
何がしか法に触れるくらい
almost bordering on illegal.
ばらまく乱心 気づけば脳頭痛
Scattering madness, before I know it, my brain is throbbing,
この世に生まれて君が悪い
your existence in this world is to blame.
やたらとしんどい 恋煩い
This love sickness is incredibly draining,
バラバラなる頭とこの身体
my head and body are falling apart.
頸動脈からアイラブユーが吹き出して
My carotid artery gushes out "I love you,"
アイリスアウト
and it's iris out.
いったいどうしよう
What on earth should I do?
この思いをどうしよう
What should I do with this feeling?
アバラの奥をザラメが溶けて
Sugar crystals are melting deep inside my ribs,
ゲロになりそう
making me feel sick to my stomach.
瞳孔バチ開いて
My pupils are completely dilated,
溺れ死にそう
I feel like I'm drowning to death.
今この世で君だけ大正解
In this world right now, you're the only correct answer.
ダーリン ダーリン
Darling, darling,
ひっくり返っても勝ちようない
Even if I flip over, there's no way to win,
君だけのルールは適用外
your rules alone are outside the system.
四つともオセロは黒しかない
All four Othello pieces are black,
カツアゲほうだい
it's complete extortion.
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラ
You cast an Avada Kedavra with a smile,
デコにスティグマ 申し訳ねえな
putting a stigma on my forehead—pardon me.
矢を刺して 貫いて
Pierce me with an arrow, run me through,
ここ弱点
this is my weak spot.
死ぬほど可愛い うわめづかい
An upturned gaze so cute it could kill,
何がしか法に触れるくらい
almost bordering on illegal.
ばらまく乱心 気づけば脳頭痛
Scattering madness, before I know it, my brain is throbbing,
この世に生まれて君が悪い
your existence in this world is to blame.
パチモンでもいい なんでもいい
I don't care if it's a knockoff, anything is fine,
今君と交づいてるすべて欲しい
I want everything that connects us right now.
頸動脈からアイラブユーが吹き出して営業日
My carotid artery gushes out "I love you,"
アイリスアウト
and it's iris out.
Ah ah ah ah ah
いったいどうしよう
What on earth should I do?
この思いをどうしよう
What should I do with this feeling?
アバラの奥をザラメが溶けて
Sugar crystals are melting deep inside my ribs,
ゲロになりそう
making me feel sick to my stomach.
瞳孔バチ開いて
My pupils are completely dilated,
溺れ死にそう
I feel like I'm drowning to death.
今この世で君だけ大正解
In this world right now, you're the only correct answer.
ダーリン ダーリン
Darling, darling,
Ah
すき
Like
キライ
Dislike
すき
Like
キライ
Dislike
すき
Like
キライ
Dislike
キライ キライ キライ キライ
Dislike, dislike, dislike, dislike
自己満 中途半端は やめて
Stop with the self-satisfying half-measures.
一番 ダサいことの体現者
The personification of the lamest things.
一生飼い犬にでも成るつもり
Are you planning on being a lapdog your whole life?
満身創痍で 血を覚醒
Covered in wounds, awaken the blood.
もういいかい
Are you ready?
まだだよ
Not yet.
もういいかい
Are you ready?
ダイスキを貫け
Pierce through with your love!
未公開
Undisclosed.
もういいかい
Are you ready?
もう もういいよね
Enough, it's enough, right?
強制 let's go!
Forced entry, let's go!
すき キライ
Like, dislike
大嫌い スキ
Hate, like
好き 嫌い
Like, dislike
嫌い、嫌い、嫌い、嫌い！
Dislike, dislike, dislike, dislike!
手鏡なんて見てないで 起死回生 先を睨め 再生
Don't look in your hand-mirror, resuscitation, glare ahead, restoration.
未体験ゾーン そうだって 自信は後からついてくる
Un-experienced zone, yes, I mean, the confidence comes afterwards.
一歩踏み出したならば cool 苦痛も鬱も続く
If you can move one step forward that's cool, pain and depression continue...
on my mind 再度確認 最初の動機をもう一度
...on my mind. Double check what my original motives were again...
思い出そう 悔しい今日 ひっくり返そう 悔しいほど
...remember now. Today's annoyance, let's turn it around, so annoying...
強く成れ 右左見たり 下を見て安心してる内は
...I can become strong. Look right and left, look down, and while relieved...
ダレにも成れない キミに成れるのはキミだけ
...you can't become anyone. You can only become yourself.
近道生み出せ リアリティー 全宇宙全世界 無二に成れ let's go!
Create a shortcut, reality, the universe, the world, become peerless, let's go!
曝け出して キミ次第で 全部変わる
Expose, depending on you, it all changes.
ベール剥がす ドロドロした中身暴く
Ripping off the veil and the muddied insides revealed.
何時の間にか見失った宝物は
Before you know it, you lost sight of it...
何処にいった ドキドキしたオープニング
...the treasure. Where did it go? This excited opening...
思い出して 初期衝動 青い春を
...remember. The early impulses, green spring...
事の最初 其れが本当 芯の誠
...the first of things. That's what's real, the core truth.
ダレも同じ 堕落 摩擦 逼わる 亘る 苦 楽
Everyone's the same, corruption, friction, the turning, changing joys and sorrows.
キミの人生 ダレの人生 一度きりの博打しようよ
Your life, whose life? One shot, let's gamble on it.
あなたはすぐに
You always...
写真を撮りたがる
...want to take pictures,
あたしはいつも
and I've always...
それを嫌がるの
...disliked that.
だって写真になっちゃえば
Because if it becomes a photograph,
あたしが古くなるじゃない
won't I grow old?
あなたはすぐに
You always...
絶対などと言う
...say things like "forever",
あたしはいつも
and I've always...
それを嫌がるの
...disliked that.
だって冷めてしまっちゃえば
Because if we cool down,
それすら嘘になるじゃない
won't even that become a lie?
don't you think?
I wanna be with you.
此処に居て
Stay here,
ずっと ずっと ずっと
forever, ever, and ever.
明日のことは判らない
We don't know what tomorrow holds,
だから ぎゅっとしていてね
so hold me tight.
ぎゅっとしていてね
Hold me tight...
ダーリン
...darling.
あなたはすぐに
You always...
いじけて見せたがる
...want to look sullen,
あたしはいつも
and I'm always...
それを喜ぶの
...happy about that.
だってカートみたいだから
Because it's like Kurt,
あたしがコートニーじゃない
and I'm not Courtney.
don't you think?
I wanna be with you.
傍に来て
Come closer to me,
もっと もっと もっと
more, more, and more.
昨日のことは忘れちゃおう
Let's forget about yesterday,
そして ぎゅっとしていてね
and hold me tight.
ぎゅっとしていてね
Hold me tight...
ダーリン
...darling.
また四月が来たよ
April has come again,
同じ日のことを思い出して
remembering that same day.
don't you think?
I wanna be with you.
此処に居て
Stay here,
ずっと...
Forever...
明日のことは 分からない
We don't know about tomorrow,
だから ぎゅっとしててね
So please hold me tight.
I wanna be with you
そばに来て
Please come to my side...
もっと もっと もっと
Come closer, closer, and closer...
昨日のことは 忘れちゃおう
Let's forget about yesterday,
そして ぎゅっとしててね
And please hold me tight.
ぎゅっとしててね
Please hold me tight,
ダーリン
Darling.
はーい！というわけで
Okay! And with that...
はろーぼー！
Hello-bo!
ホロライブ0期生 バーチャル高性能ロボットの ロボ子だよー！
From Hololive Gen 0, the virtual high-performance robot, Roboco-san!
今日は僕の誕生日ライブに来てくれて ありがとう！
Thank you all for coming to my birthday live today!
というわけで 早速『アイサウト』『DESIRE』with 常闇トワ、そして『ギラギラ』の3曲をね、歌わせていただきました！
So, I just performed three songs: "Aisout", "DESIRE" with Tokoyami Towa, and "Gira Gira"!
いかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you like them?
そして いかがでしょうか このステージ！
And how do you like this stage?!
まだね、この衣装のモチーフではないんですけど、新衣装のね、プラッシュドール衣装にちなんで作ってみました！
It's not themed after this outfit, but we designed it to match my new Plush Doll outfit!
このステージはもうさっきの3曲でもう分かるんだけど
You can probably tell from those three songs we just did...
これからどんどん化けるので 楽しみにしていてください
...but this stage will keep transforming, so look forward to it!
いろんなね姿で楽しめる。今はめっちゃ ほねほねほねほねほねー
You'll get to enjoy its various forms. Right now, it's super bony, bony, bony!
魚も骨！
Even the fish are bones!
え、めちゃめちゃ可愛くない？大好きなんだよなー そう
Isn't it super cute? I absolutely love it!
こちらはですね、海底都市がねテーマになっています
The theme here is an underwater city.
こちらの都市の名前は、冒頭のオープニングでも言っていたんですけど、アトロポリス、アトロポリスって言います
The name of this city is, as mentioned in the opening, Atrobotpolis!
ロボじゃない、ロボ。ロボ。ロボで、ロボ。
Not Robo... Robo. Robo. With Robo, it's Robo.
本来は海の底にあるね都市なんですけれども
Originally, it's a city located at the bottom of the sea...
一日だけ、ロボ子の歌のパワーで浮上させているんだよ。どう？僕、凄いでしょ？
...but for just one day, I've made it rise to the surface with the power of my singing! Pretty cool, right?
そう、ここは息吸えるの！へへへっ
That's right, you can breathe here! Hehe.
うん！
Yeah!
ぜひね いっぱい、たくさんスクリーンショット、もう撮ってるとは思うけど、いっぱい撮って
So please take lots of screenshots—I'm sure you already are, but take plenty of them!
こちらのハッシュタグもね、「#ロボ子海底3Dライブ」で、どしどしポストしていってくれると嬉しいです！
And I'd be so happy if you keep posting them using the hashtag #ロボ子海底3Dライブ!
トレンドに入りたい！よろしくお願いします！
I want to get trending! Please help me make it happen!
誕生日は終わってしまったけど、誕生日のライブのつもりでやっていますので、はい
My birthday has already passed, but I'm performing this with my birthday live spirit!
ね、いつものね、いつもやらせていただいていますので、ぜひよろしくお願いします。今回のタグは「#ロボ子海底3Dライブ」でございます。よろしくね！
Yes, just like I always do, so please show your support! The hashtag for today is #ロボ子海底3Dライブ. Thanks!
はい、というわけでね、どうでしたか？ちなみに。カッコよかった？
Alright, so how was it by the way? Was it cool?
昨年は竜とかに乗ってみたんだけど、今回はアトロポリスなんで、鮫とかにも乗ってみました！
Last year, I tried riding a dragon, but since this is Atrobotpolis, I tried riding a shark!
はい、今年もメロウな女は目指してみたくて、あの、メロウな女になっていました？
Yes, I wanted to aim to be a mellow woman again this year. Did I manage to become a mellow woman?
メロウな女。今年もメロウな女、目指したいと思います！はい。
A mellow woman... I'll keep aiming to be a mellow woman this year too! Yes.
まだね、あ、そう！気づいた？フリフリしてきたやつ。
Also... oh, yes! Did you notice? The things that were fluttering down?
実は今回は時間に余裕があったので
Actually, since we had some extra time this time...
事前にロボ部員たちにね、募集をさせていただきまして
we held a submission call for Robo Club members beforehand...
イラストが上から降ってくるようなギミックをね、用意いたしました
and we set up a gimmick where your illustrations float down from above!
採用された方はね、え？もしかして自分の絵があるのかも知れないっていうドキドキを
If yours got chosen, you can enjoy the suspense of "Wait, is my drawing going to appear?"
を味わいながら探してみてください。まだまだ出てきますのでね。
...please try searching while enjoying it. There are still many more to come.
チャンスはまだあります。
You still have a chance!
誰が、誰が書いたのが選ばれているのか、
Whose... whose drawings were chosen?
ぜひよろしくお願いします。
Please look forward to finding out!
めちゃめちゃもう可愛いやつがいっぱい出てきてますのでね。
Lots of really cute ones have been appearing.
んー、ゆっくり見てってください。
Mmm, please take your time and watch.
はい！
Yes!
それでは、まだまだありますので、
Well then, we still have more,
ここからはなんとゲストも登場するので、
and from here, guests will actually appear!
うわー！一体何を歌うんだ？！
Whoa! What on earth are we going to sing?!
楽しみにしててください！
Please look forward to it!
それじゃ、
With that said,
まだまだ行くぞー！
here we go, there's still more to come!
見てって！ポストしてって！
Watch it! Post about it!
ぽしゃ！
Pose!
一発じゃ足りないのかい
Is one shot not enough?
二発目をおかわりしたい
Do you want a second helping?
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no such thing as third time's a charm.
四の五の言うなよ ロクデモナイ
Stop complaining, you good-for-nothing.
[スターマイン]
タッタラタラッタ タッタッタ
[Song: Starmine]
Ta-ta-ra ta-ra-tta ta-tta-tta
タッタラタラッタ タッタッタ
茹だるような暑さが鬱陶しい
The sweltering heat is annoying.
夜は薄着の天使が騒々しい
The angels in light clothing are noisy tonight.
露出ばかり増えるんじゃ意味無いね
There's no point if it's just more exposure.
本当の意味での祭りはこれからのさ
The festival in its truest sense starts now.
火傷するくらいの近距離で
At a distance close enough to get burned,
仕込むスターマイン
prepare the starmine.
類を見ないような手順で
With an unprecedented procedure,
スタンバイ さぁ打ち上げろ
standby, let's set it off!
一発じゃ足りないのかい
Is one shot not enough?
二発目をおかわりしたい
Do you want a second helping?
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no such thing as third time's a charm.
四の五の言うなよ
Stop complaining.
鍵屋 玉屋
Kagiya! Tamaya!
上がってがって合点 でもねたまにゃ
Going up and up, agreed, but occasionally...
下がってがってガッデム
Going down and down, goddammit!
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no such thing as third time's a charm.
四の五の言うなよ ロクデモナイ
Stop complaining, you good-for-nothing.
タッタラタラッタ タッタッタ
Ta-ta-ra ta-ra-tta ta-tta-tta
寄ってらっしゃい 見てらっしゃい
Come on over, take a look!
でも外野はさっさと黙ってらっしゃい
But spectators, hurry up and shut up!
わっしょい わっしょい
Wasshoi! Wasshoi!
騒ぎ立てるより この瞬間大事にしない？
Cherish this moment rather than making a fuss.
未曾有の炎色反応で
With an unprecedented flame reaction,
彩るのは過去じゃなく未来だけ
coloring only the future, not the past.
息を呑むくらいのスピードで
At a speed that takes your breath away,
鳴らすスターマイン
setting off the starmine.
釘付けになるド派手さで
With an eye-catching, flashy style,
スタンバイ さぁ打ち上げろ
standby, let's set it off!
あぁ一発じゃ足りないのかい
Ah, is one shot not enough?
二発目をおかわりしたい
Do you want a second helping?
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no such thing as third time's a charm.
四の五の言うなよ
Stop complaining.
鍵屋 玉屋
Kagiya! Tamaya!
上がってがって合点 でもねたまにゃ保存
Going up and up, agreed, but occasionally...
下がってがってガッデム
Going down and down, goddammit!
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no such thing as third time's a charm.
四の五の言うなよ ロクデモナイ
Stop complaining, you good-for-nothing.
真っ黒な空を照らす
Illuminating the pitch-black sky,
命の火花散らそう
let's scatter the sparks of life.
悲しみも吹き飛ばせ保存
Blow away the sadness too.
最大火力で さぁ打ち上げろ
With maximum firepower, let's set it off!
上がってがって合点
Going up and up, agreed,
でもねたまにゃ
but occasionally...
下がってがってガッデム保存
Going down and down, goddammit!
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no such thing as third time's a charm.
四の五の言うなよ
Stop complaining.
もう一回
One more time!
上がってがって合点
Going up and up, agreed,
でもねたまにゃ 下がってがってガッデム
but occasionally, going down and down, goddammit!
三度目の正直なんてない
There's no such thing as third time's a charm.
四の五の言うなよ ロクデモナイ
Stop complaining, you good-for-nothing.
人生は七転び八起き 急展開
Life has its ups and downs, a sudden development!
タッタラタラッタ タッタッタ
Ta-ta-ra ta-ra-tta ta-tta-tta
タッタラタラッタ タッタッタ保存
[Twinkle night feat. somunia]
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
[Song: Twinkle night feat. somunia]
A night spent with you, a little urban.
処理速度高速 私から
Processing speed is fast, from me...
送るデータは膨大
The data sent is huge.
「無理、受け取れない」とかダメだよ！
"No way, I can't receive it" is a no-go!
愛して twinkle night
Love me, twinkle night.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
A night spent with you, a little urban.
キミにオーダー
...my order to you.
コマ送りメモリー
Frame-by-frame memories.
イルミの前手を取り
Taking your hand in front of the illuminations,
言葉と指を交わそうよ
let's exchange words and intertwine our fingers.
恋のセオリー
That's the theory of love.
今の暮らしは悪くなる一方です
Our current way of living is only getting worse.
君と二人暮らす部屋が理想です
A room where I live with you is my ideal.
うだつが上がらない僕のそばでずっと
By the side of useless me, forever...
笑ってくれる君が好きです
...I love that you keep smiling.
最高だよ人生 長い髪切って
Life is great! Cutting your long hair,
君の好きな誰かに合わせて
matching it to someone you like.
音楽をかけるよ 僕がDJのradio
I'll play some music like a DJ on the radio,
ポルノグラフィティみたいな感じ！どう？
just like Porno Graffitti! How about it?
目と目が合うレーザービーム
Our eyes meet like a laser beam.
漫画的偶然 手が触れた日
A manga-like coincidence, the day our hands touched.
放電する二人 電気がバチバチ
We generate a spark, the electricity crackles.
特性：蓄電、避雷針
Ability: Volt Absorb, Lightning Rod.
唐突に喋り出すSiri
Siri suddenly starts speaking.
君の言葉の裏 本当の意味
The real meaning behind your words.
これっきりギリギリで保ってるボクのハート
This is the limit, my heart is barely holding on.
プラ製でもう溶けそう
It's made of plastic and feels like it'll melt.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, a bit urban.
処理速度高速 私から
Processing at high speed, from me...
送るデータは膨大
...sending a massive amount of data.
「無理、受け取れない」とかダメだよ！
No saying, "Impossible, I can't receive it!"
愛して twinkle night
Love me, twinkle night.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, a bit urban.
甘々なひととき 君にオーダー
A sweet moment, my order to you.
コマ送りメモリー
Frame-by-frame memories.
イルミの前手を取り
Taking your hand in front of the illuminations,
言葉と指を交わそうよ
let's exchange words and intertwine our fingers.
恋のセオリー
That's the theory of love.
ティンクルくるせいだーす
Twinkle Crusaders.
Mars Attacks! ZATHURAですら
Even Mars Attacks! or Zathura...
全部架空
...are all fiction.
ヒエログリフだって
Even hieroglyphs,
誰かの解釈 読めるわけないないのにね
there's no way we can read someone's interpretation.
この物語はフィクションです
This story is a work of fiction.
君との遭遇は嘘なんです<s:
Encountering you is just a lie.
feel alright
痛くも痒くもない
It doesn't hurt, it doesn't itch.
けど黄色ゲージ、スタミナない
But the gauge is yellow, I have no stamina.
教えて Filmarks
Tell me, Filmarks:
空っぽの人生 星何点？
How many stars for an empty life?
欲しがってる満点の星
Yearning for a full starry sky,
120個 いや一個で十分かも
120 of them, or maybe just one is enough.
Wow signal 送り出す
Sending back the Wow! signal.
君は返事もくれないまま
While you still don't give me any reply.
炭酸のないサイダー
A cider without any carbonation.
飲み干せない やまだまだ
I can't drink it all down, not yet.
裸足のまま踊る夜
Dancing barefoot through the night.
寒くはないけどココアを飲む
It's not cold, but I drink hot cocoa anyway.
誰かが目てる
Someone is watching.
私も誰かを見てる
I'm watching someone too.
いちまるはち、アメと恋とゲーム
108, candy, love, and video games.
最高のfriendだ お布団
My futon is the best friend.
twinkle なんてたゆたう
Twinkle, swaying so gently.
夢遊病患者の寝言
Sleep-talking of a somnambulist.
甘い雲はバニラの香りがするんだ
The sweet clouds smell like vanilla.
包んだはずの足は寒くて引っ込めた
My feet, supposed to be wrapped up, got cold so I pulled them in.
きっとまたはみ出した
They must have slipped out again.
ままで寝てしまったんだ
I ended up sleeping like that.
末端温まったらまた
Once my toes warm up again,
彼方 あなたとなら
...beyond, if it's with you.
九日 十日
Nine days, ten days.
どうか音は星を超えた
Somehow, the sound crossed the stars.
そっか やっぱ夢か
I see, so it was a dream after all.
わかっても瞳は閉じたまま
Even though I know, my eyes remain closed.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, a bit urban.
処理速度高速 私から
Processing at high speed, from me...
送るデータは膨大
...sending a massive amount of data.
「無理、受け取れない」とかダメだよ！
No saying, "Impossible, I can't receive it!"
愛して twinkle night
Love me, twinkle night.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, a bit urban.
甘々なひととき 君にオーダー
A sweet moment, my order to you.
コマ送りメモリー
Frame-by-frame memories.
イルミの前手を取り
Taking your hand in front of the illuminations,
言葉と指を交わそうよ
let's exchange words and intertwine our fingers.
恋のセオリー
That's the theory of love.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, a bit urban.
処理速度高速 私から
Processing at high speed, from me...
送るデータは膨大
...sending a massive amount of data.
「無理、受け取れない」とかダメだよ！
No saying, "Impossible, I can't receive it!"
愛して twinkle night
Love me, twinkle night.
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world.
そういう扱い心得てよね
Make sure you know how to treat me like that.
よろしくね
Please treat me well!
ワールドイズマイン CPK! Remix
[Song: World is Mine (CPK! Remix)]
その一 いつもと違う髪形に気がつくこと
First thing: Notice when I have a different hairstyle.
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること いいね？
Second thing: Properly look down at my shoes, okay?
その三 わたしの一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Third thing: Reply with three words for every single word I say.
わかったら右手がお留守なのをなんとかして！
If you understand, then do something about my lonely right hand!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
I'm not really saying anything selfish...
キミに心から思って欲しいの「かわいい」って
I want you to think from your heart that I'm cute.
欲しいの かわいいって
I want you to think I'm cute...
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world.
気がついて ねえねえ
Realize that, hey, hey...
待たせるなんて論外よ
...keeping me waiting is out of the question.
もうなんだか
Somehow,
甘いものが食べたい！
I want to eat something sweet!
今すぐによ
Right now!
Hey baby
欠点？ かわいいの間違いでしょ 文句は許しませんの
Fault? You must mean cute! I won't allow any complaints!
あのね 私の話ちゃんと聞いてる？ ちょっと
Listen, are you actually listening to me? Hey!
あ、それとね 白いおうまさん 決まってるでしょ？ 迎えに来て
Ah, and also, a white horse is obvious, right? Come pick me up!
わかったら かしずいて 手を取って「おひめさま」って
If you understand, kneel, take my hand, and call me "princess."
べつに わがままなんて言ってないんだから
I'm not saying anything selfish at all,
でもね 少しぐらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ
but you know, it's fine to scold me a little.
世界で私だけのおうじさま 気がついて ほらほら
My only prince in the world, notice me already, come on!
お手てが空いてます
My hands are empty!
無口で不愛想なおうじさま もうどうして！
My quiet and unsociable prince, oh, why?!
気がついてよ 早く！
Notice me! Hurry!
絶対 キミは わかってない わかってないわ
You definitely don't understand, you just don't understand!
いちごののったショートケーキ
A strawberry shortcake,
こだわりたまごのとろけるプリン
and melt-in-your-mouth pudding made with select eggs...
みなみな、我慢します わがままな子だと思わないで
I'll hold back on all of them, so don't think I'm selfish.
私だってやればできるもん あとで後悔するわよ
I can do it if I try, you know! You'll regret this later.
当然です！ だってわたしは
Of course! Because I am...
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world!
ちゃんと見ててよね どこかに行っちゃうよ？
Keep your eyes on me, or I'm going to go somewhere else!
不意に抱きしめられた 急にそんな え？
Suddenly, you held me tight... Out of nowhere? Eh?
「ひかれる あぶないよ」そう言ってそっぽむくキミ
"You'll get hit, it's dangerous," you said, turning away.
こっちのが危ないわよ
...But you're the one who is dangerous to my heart.
はい！というわけで、3曲連続でお届けしましたが、どうでしたか？
Yes! And with that, I brought you three songs in a row. How was it?
Starry Jetに、え、ポルカ、べーちゃん、びぶー、そしてちは！5人で歌いました。
We sang "Starry Jet" as five people: Polka, Bae-chan, Biboo, and Chiha!
めちゃめちゃかっこよくなかった？
Wasn't it super, super cool?
え、なんかいいよね。なんかみんなで一緒に踊るのっていいよね。
It's really nice, isn't it? Dancing together with everyone is great.
そして、トウィンクルナイトをポルカと一緒に歌いました！
And I sang "Twinkle Night" together with Polka!
そして最後はワールドイズマイン、CPKのリミックスバージョンになります！
And finally, we had "World Is Mine (CPK Remix)"!
世界で一番お姫様だった？
Was I the number one princess in the world?
お姫様だった？
Was I your princess?
ここでもね、みんなに募集したイラストが降ってきましたけど、
Here, too, the illustrations we requested from everyone came falling down.
自分の見つけられた人いたかな？
I wonder if anyone was able to find theirs?
見つけたら、いっぱい写真撮っておいてくださいね。
If you found it, please take lots of photos of it, okay?
はい。というわけで、3曲お届けしたんですけど、
Yes! So, I've brought you three songs,
かっこいいもあり、かわいいもあり、いかがでしたか？
with both cool and cute ones. How did you like it?
え、そう、ステージに流れ星が、パーッて降ってきてたの、
And yeah, did you see the shooting stars raining down on the stage?
ほら見て、星空！
Look at that, a starry sky!
すごい、このステージね、マジ無限の可能性を感じるんだよね、
Incredible. I really feel like this stage has infinite possibilities.
なんでもできる気がする。
I feel like we can do anything.
うん。いや、ホロメンと一緒に歌えるの楽しいな。
Yeah. It's so much fun to sing together with other Hololive members.
いっぱいなんか、1年に1回のこのライブ、思いっきり好きなことできるのがすごい楽しい。
It's so fun to be able to do whatever I want to my heart's content on this once-a-year live.
そして衣装も久しぶりに、和装でございます。
And for my outfit, it's been a while since I wore a Japanese-style outfit.
あにゃにゃにゃ。そう、ワールドイズマインはね、
Anya-nya-nya. Yes, as for "World Is Mine"...
ちょっと、かぐやのやつで、いいなって思って、歌いたくなっちゃったので、
I really liked Kaguya's version and wanted to sing it,
せっかくだから、かぐやに合わせて、和装でね、歌ってみました。
so I decided to sing it in a Japanese-style outfit to match Kaguya.
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ。
Fault? You must mean cute, right?
ポンだっていいでしょ、まあ今日ポンはしないんですけどもね。
Being clumsy (pon) is fine too, though I won't do any clumsiness today!
なんか知らないけど、歌だけはこうせぇのって言われるしな。
For some reason, they tell me to at least do this for the songs.
はい。
Yes.
でも、今そんな、「そら」って言ってたけど、
But just now, you were saying "Sora..."
えー？今日限りでまた海に沈んじゃうんだって、この場所。
What? This place is sinking back into the sea today?
そんなのもったいないよねー。
That's such a waste, isn't it?
ロボ子さん、何かいい方法知らない？
Roboco, do you know any good way to stop it?
僕が高性能だからきっと知ってるかなって思って。
Since I'm high-spec, I thought you'd surely know.
うーん...ふん、ふん、ふん、ふん...
Hmm... Let's see...
はっ！ひらめいた！
Ah! I've got it!
海は海でも、電子の海に沈めちゃうのはいいんだ！
Even if it's a sea, sinking it into the digital sea would be perfect!
い、いいんだ！そうだよね！
Yes, that's it! Right?!
というわけで、ちょっとやっちゃおうかな？
So, I guess I'll just go ahead and do it!
お願いします！
Here we go!
パチッ。これパチッてなった？
*Click* Did it click?
悲しみの海に沈んだ私
Sinking deep into the sea of sadness,
目を開けるのも億劫
even opening my eyes is too much trouble.
このままどこまでも堕ちて行き
Falling like this, forever and ever,
誰にも見つけられないのかな
I wonder if no one will ever find me.
どこへ向かい、何をすれば？
Where am I going, and what should I do?
ふと射し込む一筋の光
Suddenly, a single ray of light shines through.
手を伸ばせば届きそうだけど
If I reach out, it feels within my grasp,
波に拐われて見失った
but it was swept away by the waves and lost.
あれは一体何だったのかな
I wonder what that really was.
あたたかくて眩しかったの
It was so warm and dazzling.
無意識のカウンターイルミネーション
An unconscious counter-illumination...
嘘つきは誰？
Who is the liar?
深海少女 まだまだ沈む
Deep sea girl, sinking further still,
暗闇の彼方へ閉じこもる
shutting herself away beyond the darkness.
深海少女 だけど知りたい
Deep sea girl, but she wants to know...
心惹かれるあの人を見つけたから
because she found the one who holds her heart.
昼も夜も無かったこの場所
In this place where there was neither day nor night,
なのに眠れない夜は続く
yet, the sleepless nights still continue.
自由の羽大きく広げて
Spreading your wings of freedom wide,
泳ぐあなたは綺麗でした
you looked so beautiful as you swam.
そしてまた光は降り注ぐ
And once again, the light pours down.
見とれていたら目が合って
As I gazed in wonder, our eyes met.
気付いてこっちを振り返るあなたに
To you, who noticed and turned to look back at me,
嘘つきな私...
a liar like me...
深海少女 わざわざ沈む
Deep sea girl, sinking on purpose,
暗闇のさなかに赤い頬
her cheeks flushing red amidst the darkness.
深海少女 ハダカの心を
Deep sea girl, showing her naked heart—
見せる勇気 黒い海がまだ許さない
the courage to show it, the black sea won't allow.
こんなに服は汚れてしまった
My clothes have become so dirty.
笑顔も醜くゆがんでいった
My smile has also warped so hideously.
誰にも合わせる顔なんて無いの
I have no face to show anyone anymore.
もう放っておいてよ！
Just leave me alone already!
声にならない気持ちが溢れてとけた
Feelings that cannot become words overflowed and melted.
次の瞬間、君が突然姿を消した
In the next instant, you suddenly vanished from sight.
心配性の 彼女は焦る
Apprehensive, she begins to panic.
闇が彼を隠しひとりきり
The darkness hides him, leaving her all alone.
限界少女 その手を伸ばす
At her limit, the girl reaches out her hand...
「ほらね、君も素敵な色を隠してた」
"Look, you too were hiding such beautiful colors."
深海少女 腕を引かれる
Deep sea girl, pulled by her arm,
歌う祝福のマリンスノー
singing the marine snow of blessings.
深海少女 もっと知りたい
Deep sea girl, wanting to know more,
心惹かれるあの人を見つけたから
because she found the one who holds her heart.
この海を出て 今飛び立つの
Leaving this sea, I fly away now!
常識、個性、理論、もっと持って
Common sense, individuality, logic, bring them on!
経済的余裕も持って、持って
Economic stability too, bring it, bring it!
喰らうは...
To consume is...
冷めた指輪もあげた
I even gave you the cooled-down ring.
王冠はしたたらと溶けたね
The crown melted away drip by drip, didn't it?
愛だの恋だのそんなんはもう合算でしょ
All that stuff like love and romance is already totaled up, right?
でも今更固執するときめっちゃいいでしょ
But clinging to it now of all times is pretty great, isn't it?
震える心 疼いてる体
A trembling heart, an aching body...
裏腹クワバラ しにたい
...contradictory feelings, I want to die.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that.
死ぬまであなたと一緒
Together with you until the day we die.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that.
あなたの顔しか顔が見えない
I can't see any face but yours.
病める時も
In sickness,
健やかなる時も
and in health,
手をとりあうのがさだめ
joining hands is our destiny.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that.
ようやくひとつになれるかな
I wonder if we can finally become one?
いつかあなたと入れ替わって
If we were to trade places someday
傷だらけになって
and get covered in wounds,
触れる肌も背中合わせ
touching skin back-to-back,
憧れが腐って
our yearning rotting away...
本当に大事なものあげた人でも
Even for the person who gave what's truly precious,
期待が普通に飲まれるのね
expectations are normally swallowed up, aren't they?
誓言ばかり並べておなじでしょ
Just listing off vows is all the same, right?
どうせ裏切り合うのが見えでしょ
It's obvious we'll just end up betraying each other anyway, right?
壊れる未来があるならば
If a broken future lies ahead,
おとぎ話なんか しにたい
then fairy tales are... I want to die.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that.
死ぬまであなたと一緒
Together with you until the day we die.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that.
あなたの顔しか顔が見えない
I can't see any face but yours.
病める時も
In sickness,
健やかなる時も
and in health,
手をとりあうのがさだめ
joining hands is our destiny.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that.
ようやくひとつになれるかな
I wonder if we can finally become one?
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that.
死ぬまであなたと一緒
Together with you until the day we die.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that.
死ぬまであなたと一緒
Together with you until the day we die.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that.
あなたの顔しか顔が見えない
I can't see any face but yours.
病める時も
In sickness,
健やかなる時も
and in health,
手をとりあうのがさだめ
joining hands is our destiny.
結婚しましょう そうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do just that.
ようやくひとつになれるかな
I wonder if we can finally become one?
ねえ ニア 誰かを笑い飛ばさなきゃ
Hey Nia, unless they laugh someone else away...
自分を許せないような くだらない人間のこと
...they can't forgive themselves. What do you think of those worthless people...
君はどう思う？
...what do you think of them?
ねえ ニア 他人の歩幅を眺めて
Hey Nia, watching other people's strides...
意味もなく駆け足になる つまらない人間のこと
...and running for no reason. What do you think of those boring people...
君はどう思う？
...what do you think of them?
Hello, Hello, I'm Nia, who are you?
Hello, Hello, I'm Nia, who are you? ねえ ニア
Hello, Hello, I'm Nia, who are you? Hey Nia,
笑顔で過ごす日々を
What do you think of those arrogant people
当たり前と思うような 傲慢な人間のこと
who take living days with a smile for granted?
君はどう思う？
What do you think of them?
カタチのないフタシかなものは いつだって
Formless, uncertain things always...
ケイサンをクルわせてしまうの
...mess up the calculations.
だけど
But...
ああ 僕はまだ信じてる
Ah, I still believe.
ココロのないキミに問いかけたのは
The reason I questioned you, who have no heart,
キミの手が僕よりもあたたかかったからさ
was because your hand was warmer than mine.
Hello, Hello, I'm Nia, who are you?
Hello, Hello, I'm Nia, who are you? ねえ ニア
Hello, Hello, I'm Nia, who are you? Hey Nia,
子供の頃に見てた
the continuation of the dream I saw as a child...
あの夢の続きがこんな
...was connected to such a future. What do you think?
ねえ、ニア...
Hey, Nia...
未来に繋がってたこと
That we were connected to the future,
君はどう思う
what do you think of that?
I am always by your side,
Nia.
ほら 僕らはまた 勘違い
Look, we made another misunderstanding,
明日のないくらい この空の下
under this sky with no tomorrow.
君の手が 僕よりも
Your hand, more than mine,
震えていた気がした
I felt it was trembling.
Hello, Hello, I'm Nia. I love you.
Hello, Hello, I'm Nia.
ねえ ニア
Hey, Nia.
誰かを笑い飛ばさなきゃ
Unless we laugh off someone else,
自分を許せないような
we can't seem to forgive ourselves.
くだらない 僕たちのこと
For our foolish selves,
君は どう思う
what do you think?
ほら 僕らはまた 期待してる
Look, we're hoping once again.
ボロボロでも 見る影もないけれど
Even if we're worn out beyond recognition,
君がいる この星を
this planet that you are on,
忘れたくはないんだよ
I don't want to forget.
ほら 僕らはまた 信じてる
Look, we're believing once again.
眠らない君に 問いかけたのは
Why I asked you who never sleeps
君の手が 僕よりも
is because your hand, more than mine,
温かかったからさ
was so warm.
Because it was so warm.
Hello, Hello, I'm Nia. I love you.
W/X/Y
作詞・作曲: Tani Yuuki
Lyrics & Composition: Tani Yuuki
垂れ流した テレビの音
The sound of the TV streaming in the background,
溜めてしまった 洗濯物は今日こそ
the laundry I left piled up, let's make sure today.
晴れてもあえて外には出ないでいよう
Even if it's sunny, we won't go outside on purpose.
映えないスナックとアルコールで乾杯をしよう
Let's make a toast with un-photogenic snacks and alcohol.
2人酸いも甘いも 噛み合わないとしても
Even if the two of us, through sweet and sour, don't quite mesh,
お互い寄り添うように 少しずらしてみようよ
let's try shifting a little bit so we can lean on each other.
君がくれた太陽 月で隠れないよう
The sun you gave me, so the moon doesn't hide it,
輝き弛まぬように歌うメロディ
singing a melody so its brilliance never relaxes.
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Frolicking, slowly flowing day,
愛してるも通り越して
going even beyond "I love you,"
似た者同士こうして
like this, as two of a kind,
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want to laugh together until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed.
Falling asleep in bed in my dreams,
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you up with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
脱ぎっぱなしの足跡辿ると
Following the footprints left behind,
不意をついて後ろから抱きつくの
catching you off guard and hugging you from behind.
つい、繰り返すと忘れてしまいそうになるよ
If I keep repeating this, I might almost forget.
振り返ると日々が当たり前じゃないこと
Looking back, realizing that everyday life isn't just taken for granted.
2人対の細胞 絡み合う特別を
A pair of cells, intertwining something special,
噛み締めて生きたいと思った まどろみ抱く正午
embracing the noon nap, wanting to live biting into those moments.
吐息、漏れた体温 微塵も逃さないよう
Breathing out, leaking body heat, not letting even a particle escape,
頭の中刻む甘いメモリー
sweet memories carved into my head.
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Frolicking, slowly flowing day,
愛してるも通り越して
going even beyond "I love you,"
違う者同士こうして
like this, as two different people,
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want to laugh together until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed.
Falling asleep in bed in my dreams,
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you up with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
重ねた手はね...
Our hands together...
ねえ 離さないでいて
Hey, don't let go of me.
ごめん これ そばにいたいだけ
Sorry, this is just me wanting to be near you.
だね
Right?
抱えた想いはお互い様でしょう
The feelings we carry are mutual, aren't they?
ほら おあいこでしょう
Look, we're even, right?
すれ違い
Misunderstandings,
間違い
mistakes...
もあるし
...we have those too,
筋書き
and things don't always
通り行かない
go according to plan,
だし
either.
悲しみだって半分こにしよう
So let's split even our sadness in half.
別れじゃない希望
It's a hope, not a parting,
独りよがりにならないようにいつも
so I won't ever end up being selfish.
君がいなきゃ今もどこかで
Without you, I'd still be somewhere...
動けないままの僕で
...unable to move forward.
ありがとう伝えたいのです
And so, I want to say "thank you."
これからは僕が支えていくって
From now on, I want to support you...
呆れてしまうくらいにね
...even to an extent that makes you roll your eyes.
I must take it day by day
面と向かうとどうしても
When we face each other, no matter what,
素直になれないな ごめんね
I can't be honest. I'm sorry.
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Playful, slowly flowing day.
愛してるも通り越して
Going far beyond just saying "I love you,"
似た者同士こうして
two of a kind, together like this...
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
...I want us to keep laughing until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed.
Falling asleep in bed in our dreams...
起こすから morning call で
...since I'll wake you up with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
はい！というわけで、今回は
Hi! So, this time...
深海少女と、それと一緒に歌った
...we had "Deep Sea Girl," and then...
2曲目、恋色、そして
...the second song, "Koiiro," and...
3曲目、W/X/Yでした！
...the third song, "W/X/Y"!
初出しの曲も何曲かあって、いかがでしたか？
I performed several songs for the first time. How did you like them?
え、深海のやつ可愛かったでしょ？
The deep sea one was so cute, right?
そう、いっぱい曲の候補あったんだけど
Yes, there were many song candidates, but...
うーん、これ！ってなったのがこちらでございました
...the ones where I went, "Ooh, this one!" were these.
これにはまたね、裏話があると思いますので
There's a backstory behind this too, so...
またお喋りしたいなと思います！
...I'd love to chat about it again!
ね！みんなのイラストもね、降ってまいりました！
And everyone's illustrations came floating down too!
可愛かったでしょ。そして...
They were so cute, right? And...
ボクのパッチンで
With my finger snap,
深海に降りてきたんだけど、ヤバくない？
I came down to the deep sea. Isn't that crazy?
ボク、パッチンの才能あったかもしんない
I might actually have a talent for snapping.
音は聞こえなかったんだけどさ
Though you couldn't hear any sound...
うーん、いけるらしい！
...well, seems like I've got it!
そして、ブランシュール衣装でございます！
And here is my Blancheur outfit!
実はこの衣装
Actually, wearing this outfit...
ライブの3Dで着るのは初めて！
...for a 3D live concert is a first!
表情もちゃんと変わります、可愛いでしょ？
My facial expressions change too. Cute, right?
ふん！
Hmph!
ね、可愛いでしょ？
See, cute, right?
今回はこちらの衣装を元に
This Artropolis was designed...
アトロポリスは作られております
...based on this outfit!
可愛い、可愛い、ふわふわ
Cute, cute, and fluffy!
あっ！これ！あっ！
Ah! This is...! Ah!
待って、これK-POPの...
Wait, this is like those K-POP...
あっ、このカメラ！あ、速い！
Ah, this camera! Oh, it's fast!
待って、ちょっと待って！
Wait, hold on a second!
K-POPのアイドルで見たことがあるカメラだ
It's that camera work you see with K-POP idols!
カメラの場所探せるの？これ
Can I actually find where the camera is?
え、待って、今のじゃ見つけられなかった！
Wait, I couldn't find it just now!
ここ！ここ！ここ！ここー！
Here! Here! Here! Over here!
おっ、うっ、どこ？
Oh, wait, where?
やばい！やばい！
This is bad! Oh no!
え、どここれ？
Wait, where is it?
手挙げてたら余計分かんないんだけど！
Keeping my hand up makes it even harder to tell!
ここ！ここ！
Here! Here!
え、ここ？
Wait, here?
うわ、違う！
Ah, wrong one!
ここ！ここ！ここー！
Here! Here! Over here!
え、合ってる？ここ！
Wait, did I get it? Here!
え、ここじゃない？
Wait, is it not here?
違うのなんか！あれれれ！
Something is wrong! Uh-oh!
ええ？次！
Huh? Next!
えー？ここー！
Huh? Over here!
分かるんだよね、ここー！
I can tell, you know. Over here!
と、いう、やばい！びっくりした！
And so... whoa! That startled me!
なんか気配を感じた
I felt a presence just now.
結構カメラ難しいのかもしれない
Tracking the camera might actually be pretty hard.
楽しかった！
That was so much fun!
というわけでね、なんとここで重大告知があります！
And with that, I actually have a major announcement!
それではこちらの動画をご覧ください
So, please take a look at this video.
どうぞ！
Here you go!
ロボ子さん 1st Album
Roboco-san's 1st Album
発売決定
Release Confirmed!
[Release Confirmed]
ロボザーのみんな、お待たせ！
Sorry to keep you waiting, Robo-fans!
ついにロボ子の1stアルバム「Jewel Memory」の発売が決定したよ！
Finally, Roboco's first album, "Jewel Memory," is confirmed for release!
これまでロボザーと一緒に過ごしてきた時間や思い出のひとつひとつが、
Every single moment and memory I've shared with my Robo-fans so far...
ロボ子にとっては宝物、宝石なんだ。
...is a treasure, a jewel to Roboco.
だから、その宝石を納めた宝箱のようなアルバムになってほしいなっていう思いを込めたよ。
So I poured my heart into making it like a treasure box filled with those jewels.
収録楽曲の順番や構成にもこだわっているから、
I was really particular about the tracklist order and composition,
楽しみにしててね。
so look forward to it!
なんと新曲も収録されるよ！
What's more, new songs will be included!
さらに同梱物にはアルバム本体を飾って保管できるアクリルケースがついてくるんだ。
In addition, the bundle comes with an acrylic case to display and store the album!
ロボ子の他のグッズと一緒に、お部屋に飾ってね。
Please display it in your room along with other Roboco merch.
他にもみんなが喜んでくれるような同梱物を用意しているよ。
We have other exciting items included that will make everyone happy.
詳細は予約ページを見てね。
Please check the pre-order page for details!
CD予約の開始はこの後21時から！
CD pre-orders start tonight at 9 PM!
ロボザーはちゃんとチェックするんだよ！
Robo-fans, make sure you check it out!
はい！ということでなんと！
Yes! And with that...
アルバムが出ます！
My album is coming out!
詳しくは販売サイト等を確認してみてください。
Please check the sales websites and such for details.
えー、お待たせしました。
Um, sorry to keep you waiting!
やっとアルバム出せた、嬉しい。
I finally get to release an album! I'm so happy!
え、めちゃめちゃカッコよくなかったですか？ビジュ。
Hey, wasn't the visual super cool?
いったい何が入っているのか。
Now, as for what's inside...
全部で10曲あるんですけれども、
There are 10 songs in total,
3曲なんと新しい、新曲ありますよ！
and three of them are brand new songs!
楽しみにしててね。
Look forward to it!
そしてこの後は、なんとそのアルバムの中から1曲の新曲、
And next, from that album, one of the new songs...
披露したいなと思います！
...I'd like to perform it!
さらにこの配信の後、
Also, after this stream...
MV、M... MV、M... MV？ん、MV？ん？
...the MV... M- MV... M- MV? Huh, MV? Wait...
分かんなくなってきたわ。
Now I'm getting confused!
MVもプレミアム公開されるので、ぜひみんなチェックしてってください！
The MV will have a YouTube premiere, so please check it out, everyone!
あ、ちなみに、
Ah, by the way,
僕の歌声にメロメロになった方は、
for those who have fallen head over heels for my voice,
今すぐメンバーに入って、
join the membership right now,
この後メンバーの、あ、配信も、
because we'll have a member-exclusive stream next.
ありますよ！
We really do!
1曲歌いますよ！
I'll sing one more song!
もうちょっとね、ロボザーと楽しみたいと思います。
I want to enjoy a bit more time with my Robo-fans.
まだこれで終わりじゃないんだからね。
It's not over yet, you know!
この配信が終わってもプレミアム動画もあるし、
Even after this stream, we have the MV premiere
メンバー限定配信もあるので、ぜひ両方とも楽しみにしててください。
and the member-only stream, so look forward to both!
新曲はみんな、
For the new song, everyone,
漢字の名前を間違えないようにしてね。
make sure not to get the kanji name wrong.
現世アリス。
Utsushiyo Alice.
ちょっとメロい、かも。
It might be a bit sweet...
それでは、最後の曲、聞いてください。
And now, please listen to the final song.
現世アリス。
Utsushiyo Alice.
不思議の国や お伽話でも
Even in wonderland or in fairy tales
見れない現実までご招待
You're invited to a reality you can't see elsewhere
現世アリス
[Utsushiyo Alice]
異国に取り残されたみたいだ
It's like being left behind in a foreign land
知らない言葉に戸惑う
Bewildered by unfamiliar words
誰も彼もが心を嘘で隠して
Everyone hides their hearts behind lies
本面を取り繕ったパレードショータイム
Masks adjusted for a parade showtime
今くらいは
At least for now...
さらけ出してよ
...lay yourself bare.
君の悔恨
Your regrets...
吐き出して見せて
...spit them all out for me.
画面越しの哀しいニュースに酔って
Intoxicated by the sad news beyond the screen,
ふと仲間の些細なノイズに怒って
suddenly angered by small noises from friends...
囚われて 流されて
Trapped, swept away,
日々に嫌気さしても
even if you get sick of these days...
忘れられぬような光景を
...a sight that cannot be forgotten,
君に届けるから
I will deliver it to you.
その目に焼き付けて見せて
So burn it into your eyes!
ねえ
Hey...
忘れさせるなんて大層な
I can't say such grand words
ことは言えないけど
as making you forget...
ちょっとでも寄り添えるように
...but to stay close to you even a little,
夜明けまで連れてくよ
I'll take you with me until dawn.
コンクリートの森を彷徨えば
If you wander through the concrete forest,
見慣れた街だって迷路
even this familiar town becomes a maze.
誰もが自分を役で演じて
Everyone plays their own role,
笑顔が貼り付いたこれが正体
with a smile plastered on—this is reality.
無理に笑わなくていい
You don't have to force a smile,
仮面なんて剥がして
just tear off that mask.
窓に映る君を抱いて
And embrace the self reflected in the window.
流行りものの空虚なダンスに舞って
Dancing to a hollow, trendy dance,
名も無き美談を人の声に倣って
parroting nameless beautiful stories in others' voices,
疑って つまずいて
doubting, stumbling,
明日に怯えても
even if you fear tomorrow.
消えやしないような感情を
The emotions that will never disappear,
君と分け合うから
I will share them with you.
その声を聞かせてみて
So let me hear your voice,
ねえ
hey...
救い出すだなんて傲慢なことは言えないけど
I can't say something as arrogant as wanting to save you, but...
ちょっとでも軽くなるように
to make things even a little lighter,
その手を引くよ アリス
I will take your hand, Alice.